<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Harper Hall</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/</link><description>Recent content on Harper Hall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Harper Hall</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/about/</guid><description>The Harper Hall is a place of learning, and of music. I have been a big fan of the Dragonrider books of Anne McCaffrey for close to 35 years. Even though I do not play any instrument and know very little of music theory, I think it a fantastic idea to distribute knowledge through song and music.
This is my little corner of the Halls of knowledge. Here I collect information and my own thoughts on a number of topic of interest to me.</description></item><item><title>The Three Holy Grails of DevOps</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/the-holy-grails-of-dev-ops/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/the-holy-grails-of-dev-ops/</guid><description>Establishing DevOps is a change in culture. It is all about trust, personal empowerment and cooperating on a larger goal.
There is neither such a thing as a DevOps-Engineer nor a DevOps team (and neither is there a Full-Stack Developer, but that is a story for another day).
But there are technical and organizational steps that help to improve the effectiveness of your organization and the quality of the services you provide.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the YubiKey</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/setting-up-yubikey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/setting-up-yubikey/</guid><description>This is my adpation of https://github.com/drduh/YubiKey-Guide
Here I skip the machine setup covery by Dr. Duh. The short of it is: you need a machine with a current kernal that is disconnecte from the network.
Below are my choices and changes. This is even more opinionated than his document.
Creating Keys Setup the environment:
$ export GNUPGHOME=$(mktemp -d) $ wget -O $GNUPGHOME/gpg.conf https://raw.githubusercontent.com/drduh/config/master/gpg.conf Generate a Pin $ tr -dc '[:upper:]' &amp;lt; /dev/urandom | fold -w 20 | head -n1 Write down the pin and keep in safe place.</description></item><item><title>Using go Dependencies from private repositories</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2021-06-private-go-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2021-06-private-go-dependencies/</guid><description>Building Docker images (using Gitlab CI) There some tutorials out there how to retrieve prviate dependencies for use in docker files like this Blog Post by Jeff Wenzbauer.
But all those I have seen require additional credentials to be created, maintained and injected. This makes using them either insecure or very cumbersome.
It think there is a simpler way by preparing a vendor directory and copying that into the builder image.</description></item><item><title>Books of Interest</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/books/</guid><description>Books of interest Unicorn Project,Gene Kim, 2019
Phoenix Project,Gene Kim, 2013
The DevOPS Handbook,Gene Kim, 2016
Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and Devops: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations,von Nicole Forsgren Phd and Jez Humble and Gene Kim, 2018
Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems,Betsy Beyer and Chris Jones and Jennifer Petoff and Niall Richard Murphy, 2016</description></item><item><title>Unified Development Platform - Lightening the Mental Load</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2021-04-lightening-the-load-unified-platform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2021-04-lightening-the-load-unified-platform/</guid><description>About a year ago I was musing with a few colleagues about the next big development in Software Engineering. My expectation was the &amp;ldquo;single unified monolith&amp;rdquo; that most team would be migrating back to. The voices saying that cloud offerings, and Kubernetes in particular, are much too complex where getting louder and louder.
At the time I did not write about it, as I had no idea, what form this monolith of serenity would take, or I would come from.</description></item><item><title>Efficient Development Checklist</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2006-06-efficient-development-checklist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2006-06-efficient-development-checklist/</guid><description>From a discussion with a few colleagues, I was assured of the impression, that while, allmost everybody in software developments knows three things: a) the process (what process?) in most organisations is broken and b) everybody has heard that other, larger better organisations use modern methods (”Oh, that, yes I read about &amp;lt;fortune 500 company&amp;gt; is doin’ it.”) and nobody is using it themselfs, for various reasons. Myself included.
There are a number of small things that you can introduce piece by piece into your development process and see if they work.</description></item><item><title>The Server War</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2005-12-the-server-war/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2005-12-the-server-war/</guid><description>For the last few years Microsoft Server Software and Linux Products have not realy been competing very much. Both sides where too busy gobbling up the large chunks of market real-estate that where left dormant by makers of large scale servers, who where unable to offer efficient and easy to use entry-level servers. Also the market for those entry class servers was growing and this class of servers was continuosly moving onto higher and higher ground as the performance parameters of off-the-shelf PCs grew in leaps and bounds.</description></item><item><title>Getting back control of information dissemination</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2005-12-getting-back-control-of-information-dissemination/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/post/2005-12-getting-back-control-of-information-dissemination/</guid><description>In a recent Op-Ed piece John Seigenthaler Sr., lets us know about his understandable dissattisfaction with the contents of the Wikipedia entry about his person. He rants about the inability of legal discourse against libelous writers and prophecies a dark future where everybody can say what he wants to say.
I completely agree with Mr. Seigenthaler that libelous content anywhere should answer to legal discourse. His further actions document that, while difficult in the maze of participants (the service provider wikipedia, the ISP of the original writer, BellSouth, and the yet unkown original author of the ‘pedia entry), he can file a suit agains John Doe and persue due course of the law to take the perpetrator to task.</description></item><item><title>Things of Interest</title><link>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/things-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cypherfox.github.io/harper-hall.de/pages/things-of-interest/</guid><description>Things of (my) Interest This is a curated list of links on topics that I am interested in. I try to keep it up to day in irregular intervals.
Architecture Wardley Maps Arc42 Arc42 Template Overview a set of documentation templates that help you organize information and process on designing software architectures.
Software Development [https://www.youtube.com/c/ContinuousDelivery/videos](Continous Delivery): Youtube Channel of Dave Farley, Co-Author of &amp;ldquo;Continous Delivery&amp;rdquo;. Insightful content on all things software development process.</description></item></channel></rss>