<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Harper Hall</title><link>https://harper-hall.de/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Harper Hall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harper-hall.de/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Three Holy Grails of DevOps</title><link>https://harper-hall.de/pages/the-holy-grails-of-dev-ops/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harper-hall.de/pages/the-holy-grails-of-dev-ops/</guid><description>Establishing DevOps is a change in culture. It is all about trust, personal empowerment and cooperating on a larger goal.
There is neither such a thing as a DevOps-Engineer nor a DevOps team (and neither is there a Full-Stack Developer, but that is a story for another day).
But there are technical and organizational steps that help to improve the effectiveness of your organization and the quality of the services you provide.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the YubiKey</title><link>https://harper-hall.de/pages/setting-up-yubikey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harper-hall.de/pages/setting-up-yubikey/</guid><description>This is my adpation of https://github.com/drduh/YubiKey-Guide
Here I skip the machine setup covery by Dr. Duh. The short of it is: you need a machine with a current kernal that is disconnecte from the network.
Below are my choices and changes. This is even more opinionated than his document.
Creating Keys Setup the environment:
$ export GNUPGHOME=$(mktemp -d) $ wget -O $GNUPGHOME/gpg.conf https://raw.githubusercontent.com/drduh/config/master/gpg.conf Generate a Pin $ tr -dc '[:upper:]' &amp;lt; /dev/urandom | fold -w 20 | head -n1 Write down the pin and keep in safe place.</description></item><item><title>Books of Interest</title><link>https://harper-hall.de/pages/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harper-hall.de/pages/books/</guid><description>Books of interest Unicorn Project,Gene Kim, 2019
Phoenix Project,Gene Kim, 2013
The DevOPS Handbook,Gene Kim, 2016
Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and Devops: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations,von Nicole Forsgren Phd and Jez Humble and Gene Kim, 2018
Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems,Betsy Beyer and Chris Jones and Jennifer Petoff and Niall Richard Murphy, 2016</description></item><item><title>Things of Interest</title><link>https://harper-hall.de/pages/things-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harper-hall.de/pages/things-of-interest/</guid><description>Things of (my) Interest This is a curated list of links on topics that I am interested in. I try to keep it up to day in irregular intervals.
Architecture Wardley Maps Arc42 Arc42 Template Overview a set of documentation templates that help you organize information and process on designing software architectures.
Software Development [https://www.youtube.com/c/ContinuousDelivery/videos](Continous Delivery): Youtube Channel of Dave Farley, Co-Author of &amp;ldquo;Continous Delivery&amp;rdquo;. Insightful content on all things software development process.</description></item></channel></rss>